# **SUJON MIA**

Mirpur 1, Dhaka • 01743776488 • sujonbdjoin019@gmail.com

GitHub - Linkedin

#### **SUMMARY**

I have about two years of Experience in Laravel, I am a full-stack web application developer with strong skills in PHP, and Laravel. I am expertise in bootstrap and material UI for frontend design and complex SQL query execution for the backend with Jquery & Ajax. I have experience with API creation by Laravel for the frontend. I am cooperatively strong in the backend but have enough experience in full-stack

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer, My Outsourcing Ltd.

May 2023 - Present

- Updated and streamlined existing code to improve site performance for the entire company.
- Determining the structure and design of software.
- Maintain and enhance existing projects
- Performed testing and collaborated with teams
- Big data and traffic handling with the most effective data structure and minimal hardware resource usage.
- I have worked at IDLC, STL, Nestle, Square Hospital, Eye Hospital, Rangs Workshop, and more.

# Web Developer, Mamurjor-IT

June 2021 - Fed 2023

- Managed project timelines, reducing delivery times by 30%.
- Spearheaded the adoption of cutting-edge engineering software, improving project accuracy by 15%.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, enhancing project success rates by 10%.

#### Web Developer, DTerms

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

- Coordinated project tasks, ensuring adherence to engineering standards and regulations.
- Conducted comprehensive project analyses, identifying and rectifying discrepancies in engineering designs.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BSC In Computer Science & Engineering**

2024 Present

Southeast University, 252, Tejgaon Industrial

# **Diploma In Engineering: Computer Technology**

2016-2020

Bogura Polytechnic Institute, Bogura

### **SKILLS**

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, jQuery, Javascript, Vue Js (Learning)
- Backend: PHP, Laravel, API Development
- Database: MySql
- Tools: Cpanel, WHM, s3, VPS Server (Basic)
- Soft Skill: Project Management, Problem Solving, Creativity, Critical situation handling, WordPress Customization